it's April 29th 2009 teen and I'm with
CIA whistleblower John Kiriakou well not
history with them I'm in Holland here
comes Jesus called both cars popped in
Dutch with a meth with a candle it's
just a regular podcast and that's John
Kiriakou welcome to be with where are
you currently I am in Washington DC one
of the ugliest and most build cities in
the world
I talked to Barrett Brown the other day
and he was complaining about Dallas also
so what is the cool place to be then
well it might be the cool place to be is
Los Angeles it's the only place where I
feel like I can relax I just love it
there okay I haven't been there myself
so why don't you move then would you
move or no I would but I have five
children and they're here so yeah I have
to put my own wants and desires a second
yeah I suppose I can relate I have two
kids here and they say well whatever we
want to do we cool with that we were not
moving we live here okay all right so
John what I want to do in this interview
is get to know you
what have you been doing for the past I
don't know 10 20 years since you're
known as a CIA whistleblower so how did
that happen
you disclose the fact that United States
was torturing people waterboarding them
in Guantanamo Bay now after we did that
I want to move into yeah how you your
view on the world if you will on
operations like that on CIA and and then
so for starts what did you do like into
10 20 years prior to their throat
blowing whistle on CIA I do the CIA in
January 1990 I spent the first seven
years of my career there as an analyst
working on Iraq I got bored and I'm a
linguist I speak both Greek and Arabic
and so I switched to counterterrorism
operations in 1997 I served overseas and
a lot of different places mostly in the
Middle East working on counterterrorism
mostly working against al-qaeda and then
after the 9/11 attacks I became the
chief of CIA counterterrorism operations
in Pakistan it was in that position that
I led a series of raids that resulted in
the capture of Abu Zubaydah who we
believed at the time to be the number
three in al-qaeda return to headquarters
in the middle of 2002 I was promoted on
the strength of the Abu Zubaydah capture
and I became the executive assistant to
the CIA's deputy director and and
participated I'm ashamed to tell you in
the in the planning for the Iraq war
which many of us opposed both inside the
CIA and outside but the decision had
already been made at the White House
that's an issue for a different
conversation of course I left the CIA in
2004 and I went into the private sector
now when I got back from Pakistan and
this is kind of the crux of the whole
thing I was asked if I wanted to be
trained in what a senior officer called
the use of enhanced interrogation
techniques I had never heard that term
before this was in June May or June of
2002 and I asked him what it meant and
he got very excited and he he said we're
gonna start getting rough with these
guys and I said well what does that mean
rough and he described these ten
techniques and I said that sounds like a
torture program no no it's been approved
by the president it's not torture and I
said no I said that I said I have a I
have a moral and ethical problem with
that I don't want to be involved with
that at all and so I wasn't and I went
on to work on Iraq again so I left the
CIA in 2004 and I actually waited
for somebody to come forward and say
something about the torture program and
nobody said anything I was like who at
the time was also a senior CIA officer
when is when is somebody gonna say
something I mean this is so clearly
illegal certainly somebody is going to
come out and and say we need to stop
this and nobody did and so to make a
long story short in December of 2007 I
finally decided that I would say
something I did not go through my teen
of command remember I was no longer than
CIA but more importantly it was my chain
of command that created the torture
program Congress because it was Congress
that approved the torture program and
that funded the torture program and so
the only place to go was to them to the
media to the press and I agreed to give
an interview to ABC News here in
Washington in which I said three things
they said the CIA was torturing its
prisoners they said torture was official
US government policy it was not the
result of a rogue officer as the
president had said and I said that the
torture program had been personally
approved by the president so as you can
imagine the FBI began investigating me
the very next day and they investigated
me for a full year from December of 2007
to December of 2008 and they decided in
December of 2008 that I had not
committed a crime and they closed the
case
three weeks later Barack Obama became
president and I had no idea that he
asked the Justice Department to secretly
reopen the case against me Oh secretly -
really I had no idea I was under
surveillance I had no idea that my
phones were being tapped I had no idea
that the Justice Department was reading
my emails and they did that for three
more years and finally in January of
2012 I was arrested I was charged with
five felonies including three counts of
espionage all coming out of that ABC
News interview
all the time that you will be
investigated that's what's the time that
you wrote your book Oh No during the
time I was being investigated not only
did I write a New York Times bestselling
book about my experience but I was hired
by John Kerry to be the chief
investigator on the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee so here you have the
chief investigator on the most
prestigious and important committee on
Capitol Hill I'm under secret
investigation by the FBI for espionage
what's Congress a president must have
been aware of the program but what do
you think in hindsight was Congress
aware at that time also they were
totally aware and they all pretended
that they weren't they all pretended
that their hands were clean that's
something that our politicians do quite
well here oh not just over there it's a
common thing all right so well the guy
investigating you in secret that's
somebody who's known in Holland for the
Russian collusion investigation mr.
Muller right I think I think I think the
people of Holland aren't aware of just
about everybody that was involved in my
case John Brennan and I I've known John
for thirty years John Brennan the former
CIA director was the one that asked the
Justice Department to reopen the case
against me and it was because John had a
nick Sounion obsession with leaks with
national security leaks so John asked
the Justice Department to open the case
robert muller was the chief of the FBI
at the time he created something called
the John Kiriakou task force which went
on to spend 6 million dollars of the
taxpayers money following me everywhere
I went
reading my mail listening to my phone
calls and then when I was finally
arrested it was an FBI agent by the name
of Peter struck who actually physically
put the handcuffs on me Peter Strock was
the FBI agent implicated in the mother
case for plotting against the president
all these same people who were involved
in the Muller investigation John Brennan
Muller himself Peter Strunk Eric Holder
these were all the same people that went
after me this is what they do
yeah well now that's what they do okay
fair enough but but this particular
focus on you
that was new I suppose who went before
you with that all that focus or were you
at first I was not the first Tom Drake
was the first okay okay Jeffrey sterling
came after Tom Drake I was the third and
it Snowden came after me it was a it was
a line of line of us and remember we we
have this law here in the United States
called the Espionage Act the Espionage
Act was written in 1917 to combat German
saboteurs between 1917 and 2009 three
Americans were arrested with espionage
for speaking to the press but just under
Barack Obama eight of us were arrested
and charged with espionage for speaking
to the press that's almost three times
the number of all previous presidents
combined and it was because of people
like John Brennan and Robert Muller who
were advising Barack Obama yeah so let's
go into that a little bit more than so
when when Obama was elected I remembered
it vividly I was cheering it on so this
is a good thing yeah I even took my
children to witness the be inauguration
there you go well the Washington Mall
with all the guitarists and your heroes
and stuff so were we wrong or did
something change after that we were
wrong and I'll tell you why there was a
book that was published in 2013 called
Double Down written by by Mark Halperin
and John hilemon they're two eminent
political reporters here in the United
States Barack Obama agreed to sit for an
interview for this book and he said two
things that were shocking
he said very plainly matter-of-factly he
said I never said I was a liberal just
like that I never said I was a liberal
we believed that he was a liberal but he
was a fake and the other thing that he
said that was shocking he was talking
about the drone program and he said I
never had any idea that I would be so
good at killing people that was Barack
Obama we hated george w bush so much we
wanted out of iraq so badly that we
tricked ourselves into thinking that
barack obama was going to be our savior
and in many ways he was worse than
george w bush okay if we extend that so
we had the second bush that we had Obama
what's your take on Trump Trump's even
worse than Obama was I was just talking
to one of my attorneys last night and my
attorney told me that there are three
times the number of national security
leak investigations going on right now
than in there in the worst year of the
Obama administration so we thought Obama
was bad because he eight people compared
to you know three in the previous
history of the United States there are
123 leak investigations taking place
right now it's unprecedented in American
history so is that the president's
administration that's initiative Inglis
or you think yes yes this president
specifically and even more granularly it
was Attorney General Jeff Sessions now
sessions is gone and he's been replaced
by William bar but those investigations
are ongoing so it's administration it's
Donald Trump pushing this issue okay
okay so back to your story in 2012 you
were convicted even though under the
Bush administration they thought well no
not too much went on so what
what specifically where you're convicted
for yeah so I was charged with five
felonies including three counts of
espionage
I hadn't committed espionage clearly it
was facing forty five years in prison
and I decided to go to trial because I
knew in my heart I had done nothing
wrong what I had done was in the public
service and so I decided to go to trial
well I went before Judge Leonie brinkema
she's the judge that is handling the
Assange case she's the judge that is
handling the Snowden case she's the
judge that put Jeffrey sterling in
prison
she's a hanging judge so she denied my
70 requests to declassify 70 different
documents necessary to defend myself as
a result I had no defence my defense was
classified and I couldn't I couldn't say
classified information in in court that
would have been actually ironically
another espionage charge so my lawyers
said I said well what do we do we've
just we've just lost our defense and my
lawyer said now we have to talk about
taking a plea and so this is what our
Justice Department does they'll charge
you it's called charge stacking they'll
heat multiple charges on you knowing
that you haven't committed these crimes
and then once you go bankrupt they offer
to drop all the charges if you take a
plea to a lesser charge that's where
they win ninety eight point two percent
of their cases according to Pro Publica
you know I say often we used to laugh
when Saddam Hussein would run for
re-election and he would win 98 percent
we would laugh and say what a joke the
fix was in but the Justice Department
wins 98 percent of its cases and we say
they're geniuses everybody's a criminal
well the fix is in the system is corrupt
and so they told me to decide do 23
months in prison take a guilty plea to
confirming the surname of a former CIA
colleague even though the name was never
made public do 23 months in prison or
to trial and I said I'm gonna go to
trial when I called my lawyers to tell
them I said listen my wife and I were up
all night long we talked about this all
night long we decided we're gonna go to
trial as soon as I can get in front of a
jury they're gonna see how ridiculous
this is
and one of my lawyers drove over to the
house he was very angry and he pointed
at me and he said you know what your
problem is your problem is you think
this is about justice and it's not about
justice
it's about mitigating damage take the
deal
and he was right I said to him if I
don't take the deal and I lose what am I
looking at and he said you're looking at
18 to 24 years I knew it
done anything wrong I knew that no no
national-security defendant has ever won
a case in front of Judge Leonie brinkema
so what was I gonna do I have five
children at home my ear said this can be
a blip in your life or it can be the
defining event of your life make it the
blip and so I took the deal well maybe
if you tell it like this accepting that
that there is no rule of law that the
justice system doesn't work the way you
shoot that that's the hard part of
accepting that even more so even after
everything that I had gone through that
previous year or even the previous you
know five years I believed until that
day in the rule of law I really believed
naively in retrospect I believed that if
you were innocent you would be found
innocent I believed that you could find
justice in the US justice system and I
learned the hard way that this the
system is fixed the stacked you cannot
win a case okay all right well you you
well you got out of prison in 2015
you won on a different level by winning
a Sam Adams Award for integrity how was
that that was good yeah um there's a
group of retired intelligence officers
from the CIA the NSA the Defense
Department and the FBI and they're
called Sam Adams associates every year
they give out an award for integrity and
intelligence and and just as soon as I
got out of prison they gave me the the
award for integrity and tout in
intelligence and it's funny it's funny I
I've won a lot of awards the the funny
part of this is that this whole thing
has made me famous here in the States
and it's made me a champion of of civil
rights and civil liberties and human
rights and rule of law and this is not
something that I ever thought it just
happened and so I wrote a book when I
was in prison and I won the the pen
First Amendment award for this book it's
one of the four they call it the big
four the pen First Amendment the
pen/faulkner the Pulitzer Prize and the
Edgar Allan Poe
so I the pen First Amendment award I won
the Sam Adams integrity and intelligence
award I won the blueprint for free
speech award for courage and integrity
in whistleblowing did that that's what
that one was called there's a Republican
a conservative Republican group here in
Washington called the committee for the
Republic and they gave me there it was
it was the annual award for honesty and
integrity in rule of law so you know if
the if the White House and the Justice
Department thought that they were going
wreck me with this prosecution they made
me a star here has been fired mercifully
massively and now I have a silk box I
have a venue where I have access to the
media and I can talk about these issues
like you and I are talking about them
nothing they can do to stop me
now this whole thing with you started
because of that torture program that you
were asked for and it you didn't want to
do and then later blew the whistle on
how did that proceed after that are we
still torturing in Guantanamo Bay or
other locations well that's that's
really a great question so what happened
didn't when I when I first blew the
whistle as they denied it and denied it
and denied it and then they said okay
they finally admitted it the reason why
they finally admitted it is because one
of my biggest supporters was Senator
John McCain McCain had been tortured in
Vietnam tortured mercilessly and in fact
permanently lost the use of his arms he
couldn't lift his arms up more than 45
degree angle and so he came to my
defense
even after I went to prison he came to
my defense and it was pressure from
McCain based on the information that I
had provided that resulted in passage of
the McCain fine stein amendment
amendment which permanently banned
torture in the United States and McCain
said when when McCain Feinstein was
finally passed that the American people
would not have known that their
government was torturing prisoners had I
not said something and so in the end
even though I went to prison for two
years for 23 months it was worth it
because it really did and torture in
this country did it it did yeah so about
I do not know all of American
journalists and stuff so I have no idea
who Kevin Barrett is but he claimed not
so long ago that current CIA director
Gina Haspel got into that role because
she approved of torture as a as a as a
means yes yes that's true I worked for
Gina in the CIA's Counterterrorism
Center I've known Gina for many many
years
Tina's a monster Gina I believe is a
sociopath when when we were working in
the counterterrorism center together
just after I turned down the torture
training Gina flew out to one of this
prisons just for the purpose of watching
a torture session she wanted to
participate in it just because she
enjoyed it so when Gina was first
nominated the Washington Post called me
and asked me if I would write an op-ed
saying why she was the wrong person for
the job and I wrote 1,200 words they
gave me front-page coverage and the day
that it ran it was a Sunday I got a call
from Senator Rand Paul of Kentucky he's
the kind of a libertarian Republican and
he asked me to come to his office to
strategize to see how we could defeat
Gina hospitals nomination I said done so
I drove up to Capitol Hill and we met
all day coming to a strategy where we
could convince Republicans his
Republicans have the majority of the US
Senate we could convince Republicans
that Gina was the wrong person for this
job
and I went on television and I said look
I think it's wonderful that the
president wants to nominate a woman to
be the CIA director it's it's far past
time that a woman should be the CIA
director not this woman that I could
name 70 women that would be outstanding
CIA directors this one is a war criminal
this one has committed crimes against
humanity this is the wrong message to
send to the CIA workforce what is the
message of naming Gina Haspel the
message is you can commit war crimes you
can commit crimes against humanity you
can carry out a torture program you
could murder people in cold blood and
not only will you not be prosecuted
you'll be promoted and indeed you could
become the director of the CIA
so who elder who put her into office
then who is that the President or yes
Donald Trump put her into office but the
Democrats are just as responsible
because at the very last
minute five prominent important
Democrats including my own Senator John
Warren forgive me a Mark Warner who is
the highest ranking Democrat on the
Intelligence Committee switched sides
and voted YES on Jena houseboat all
right all right that's that's that's not
so hopeful let's let's let's try we end
with the candle again yeah with misses
of hope you have to come up with one
didn't mail it coming fifteen minutes if
we come back in time - after world world
- back in the day there was no CIA and
President Truman in started a thing and
to my knowledge you know just add or
correct me or whatever but there was a
separate entity that doesn't report to
the president's office correct no no
directly to the president's office see
this was this was the controversy back
then in 1947 during this world war there
was no intelligence service and so
President Roosevelt created something
called the Office of Strategic Services
but it was operational not analytic so
they would take Greek Americans like me
who spoke Greek they would put them
behind Nazi lines - to provide
operational support and arms to the
Greeks or the Italians or the Russians
or whomever when the war ended the
Office of Strategic Services was
disbanded it went away in 1947 President
Truman decided to create the CIA under
something called in the National
Security Act of 1947 now the only reason
that he was successful in doing that is
he convened he convinced J Edgar Hoover
the longtime director of the FBI that
the CIA would be a very small entity and
it would report to the FBI it would be a
division of the FBI that was a lie he
said that only to keep Hoover away so
Hoover stayed it stayed out of the way
so the National Security Act of 1947
created the CIA and it was after passage
that Hoover realized that the CIA was an
independent entity
that reported directly to the president
well that was great for a few years but
then the CIA started doing things like
it stole the Italian election of 1948
right it financed the Christian
Democrats the Christian Democrats beat
the communists who were ascendant in
Italy that was the first first election
that the CIA stole they overthrew the
Mossadegh government in Iran in 1953
they overthrew the government of the
Dominican Republic in 1953 they
overthrew the government of Guatemala in
1954 well by then
Truman's not president anymore and he
realizes I've made a terrible mistake
I've created a monster and there's no
oversight
well when John Kennedy was finally
elected president in 1960 he told a
paramour that the CIA was a terrible
mistake and that he intended his words
he intended to break it into a thousand
pieces and scatter it to the wind and
then he was murdered three weeks later
and so President Johnson who became
president upon Lincoln's unblinking a
punt carryover cuts it for him Lincoln
memorabilia Johnson was a supporter of
the CIA and the CIA ran wild through the
years of the Vietnam War until 1975 so
they've been unchecked from 1947 to 1975
in 1975 things tipped we had lost the
Vietnam War and news news had been
released that the CIA had been actively
assassinating foreign heads of state
right just going in and shooting people
blowing up presidents and prime
ministers and overthrowing governments
and Congress finally stepped in there
were two committees one called the
church committee and the other was
called the pike committee in the house
the church was in the Senate
was in the house and they held the first
ever open hearings on CIA assassinations
and they decided that the CIA was out of
control
it had to be reined in and they created
the Senate Select Committee on
Intelligence and the house permanent
Select Committee on Intelligence to
oversee the CIA that worked great until
9/11 and then when 9/11 happened a
decision was made both at the White
House and on Capitol Hill that we needed
to just let the CIA go and do whatever
it needs to do they gave the CIA
literally an unlimited budget and they
said kill everybody that you need to
kill and now we find ourselves in the
situation where we find ourself oh well
that was a time where this interview
started where where United States went
to war in Iraq right so if you could let
me tell you about Iraq for one second we
we have I know ten minutes but I'll make
us quick the Iraqis were no threat to us
the Iraqis had no weapons of mass
destruction we knew they had no weapons
of mass destruction and even if they had
them they had no delivery systems so the
Iraqis were no threat to us when I
returned from Pakistan and I got this
promotion to become the executive
assistant to the deputy director I I
went on my first day and I said okay I
said to the deputy director I said so
what are we doing and he said you know
what I can't tell you until you sign
some secrecy agreements you have to go
upstairs to the seventh floor and sign
these secrecy agreements so I did I went
upstairs I six different agreements and
I said so what are we doing and the man
said okay here's the deal
he said next year in February we're
going to invade Iran we're gonna
overthrow Saddam Hussein we're gonna
open the world's largest Air Force Base
in southern Iraq and we're going to move
all of our air forces out of the
Arabian Peninsula into Iraq to deprive
some of the modern of the ability to say
that we were polluting the land of the
Two Holy Mosques I was shocked into
silence and all I could think to say was
but we haven't caught bin Laden yet and
he's like this he said listen the
decisions been made
the battle lines have been drawn he said
the pro-war factions are the office of
the vice president the office of the
Secretary of Defense and the National
Security Council the anti-war factions
and this is going to sound crazy the
anti-war factions were the CIA the Joint
Chiefs of Staff and the State Department
and I said if the CIA and the Joint
Chiefs are anti-war why are we doing it
they're doing this and he said as we
work for the president and the president
told us to do it okay and that was it we
went to war for no good reason if you
fast forward to today where United
States is putting ever ever ever more
pressure on Venezuela
who is doing that then is that the
president's office or is the CIA oh no
it's it's the president's office and I
can't even tell you who inside the
president's office first of all this
president doesn't even he couldn't
locate Venezuela on a map it's not it's
not him he's too stupid to do it it's
john bolton the national security
advisor who is one of the most dangerous
men in America and it's Elliott Abrams a
convicted criminal from the George HW
Bush administration and again from the
George W Bush administration Elliott
Abrams was the one who was responsible
for the iran-contra affair
it was Elliott Abrams who spent 12 years
working for Republican presidents
overthrowing Latin American governments
this is what he does and now he is the
senior director at the National Security
Council for Latin America so it's John
Bolton and Elliott Abrams they hate
Venezuela
they hate nicolas maduro and all they
want is to install a right-wing
strongman in venezuela who will do what
we tell him to do
yeah well is it mere hate like emotion
or is it the oil reserves of money what
about you know a year ago I would have
said it was it was just hate it was
ideology I'm more cynical than that now
and and I finally allowed myself to
believe that these that these wars these
conflicts are always about money their
ways about oil were there about fair
earth metals or they're about access to
water
whatever the reason you know a friend of
mine said in 1991 I went into Kuwait
with the Marines on Liberation Day and
we reopen the American Embassy there we
pushed Iraqi troops out and I said to
this colleague of mine I said I am so
proud and so excited to be a part of
this historic day we're liberating this
country for the Kuwaiti people and he
said to me [__] instead if they had
gravel instead of oil do you think we
would be here today and he was right
it's always about the oil it's is about
the metals or about gold or water or
something it's always about money all
right we still have this obligation to
end this thing on a positive note that
we have like like five or six minutes
left there's two things I there's still
things I want to talk about with you in
the remaining minutes that you gave me
so one is what's going on with Julian
Assange and the other one is how does
Holland NATO EU fit into this thing so
let's start with asan she was taken out
of t I could or an embassy sitting in a
jail it and UK now what's your take on
that I regularly touch with Julian and I
wish I had good news to tell you that
none of this is good I think that
eventually he'll be extradited to the
United States and eventually he'll face
espionage charges here which is
unprecedented in American history
Julian's job really the job of Julian's
defense attorneys is to prove that
Julian is a journalist which he is he's
a publisher and frankly I Bray I blame
much of Julian's problems on the
American media the big media the New
York Times The Washington Post CNN I
blamed them because they've turned on
him and if this administration or any
other administration can go after a
legitimate journalist and prosecute him
under the Espionage Act for doing his
job as a journalist then every
journalist is in danger
that's the end of our constitutional
rights to freedom of the press and to
freedom of speech and so they're going
to have to come together and support
Julian they're not there yet so I'm not
optimistic about Julian's near and
medium-term situation so he's in this
this awful prison in London right now
awaiting extradition he could actually
delay extradition by appealing to the
European Court of Human Rights for as
long as five years but eventually he's
going to find his way here to the United
States and he's gonna have a difficult
time so that I worry about very very
much yes wait the embassy yeah would you
like to close on that sure okay I'll let
you have to explain what's going on that
not too many people know about that
so the US government is expelled all
Venezuelan diplomats we have we've
severed diplomatic relations with with
Venezuela which is a terrible stupid
short-sighted mistake and we have
arbitrarily recognized this nobody named
Juan Guido as the president of Venezuela
who is one wydo wydo wydo is a former
graduate student from George Washington
University right down the street he's a
nothing he's a nobody even Venezuelans
didn't have any idea who he was until
until Elliott Abrams decide
that this guy is going to be the
president of Venezuela he's never even
been elected to anything nationwide in
Venezuela he got himself elected to the
popular assembly but just in a very
small district he's not a national
figure in Venezuela by any stretch of
the imagination on top of that even if
the rest of the world had recognized him
the benefit Constitution says that in
the event of an overthrow of the
government three elections have to be
held within 30 days days have come and
gone and there haven't been any
elections and wydo hasn't been elected
president but but the United States is
forcing him on the people of Venezuela
on the Organization of American States
on the European Union and and so the
battle lines have been drawn so what
we've done here in Washington is about
four dozen of us have at the invitation
of the Venezuelan government the
legitimate Venezuelan government Maduro
government right the Maduro government
that's what you mean you don't have to
like Nicolas Maduro I don't but the man
is the democratically elected president
of Venezuela so to respect that respect
the Constitution respect the rule of law
so at the at the invitation of the
Maduro government we've taken over of
the Venezuelan embassy in Washington and
we sleep in it every night dozens of us
we sleep in it to protect it from the
Secret Service the Secret Service has
surrounded it and they're threatening to
to breach the embassy to enter the
embassy and take it over and turn it
over to supporters of wydo but so long
as we're inside they have to prepare for
a fight and we're not giving it up so
that will be a fight against United
States citizens in inside there yeah
it'll be Americans fighting Americans
inside the Venezuelan embassy
well that sounds only fair after Asajj
be arrested inside the Ecuadorian
Embassy no much for diplom
a community for anybody what the what
the the Dutch can do and the European
Union and such you know I traveled to
Europe a lot I've addressed the European
Parliament three times since 2015 on
exactly these issues and I even met with
Angela Merkel's national security
adviser last time I was in Berlin
there's actually a lot that Europeans
can do and that is that you have to you
have to push your elected officials
especially your representatives to the
European Parliament to to conduct and to
carry out an independent foreign policy
don't fall under the spell of the United
States this is a mistake this this war
mongering foreign policy that we demand
of our allies it's just a mistake both
in the short term and in the long term
if anything we should be we should be
promoting the cause of peace we should
be promoting the sanctity of borders we
should be promoting economic integration
we should be promoting human rights and
civil liberties rather than picking
fights with other countries around the
world and that's what we've been doing
for years we just pick fights and so
frankly what we need here is European
leadership because conceded leadership
you're not going to get any leadership
on these issues from the United States
well not you have any ambitions or run
for office or not you know what okay so
I'll see what we can do on this end of
the ocean Jonas thank you so much for
talking to us Mike
[Music]
you